Maxime St-Onge Amoretti

Backend Software Developer

💌 maxime.stongea@gmail.com 💡 Toronto, Canada 🙎 English, French, Spanish 🤘 maxamoretti.com

PROFILE

I am a strong independent problem solver who loves contributing to vibrant teams. After spending three years working as an actuarial associate in the insurance industry, I decided to re-skill in May 2022 to become a software developer.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Co-Creator, Software Developer

Jan 2023 – present

Otter (otter-framework.dev) *⊘*

Otter is a cloud native framework to easily integrate peer-to-peer video communication within web applications.

- Engineered an auto-scaling serverless infrastructure on AWS to enable WebRTC functionality into web applications (HTTP/WebSocket API Gateways, Lambda functions, ECS with Fargate, and DynamoDB).
- Wrote a CLI tool to automate the provisioning and teardown of AWS cloud infrastructure (AWS CLI).
- Developed a frontend application for private 1-on-1 meetings hosted by Otter (CloudFront with S3 Bucket). Features include low latency audio/video communication, instant messaging, and file sharing.
- Containerized and deployed CoTURN, an open-source implementation of STUN/TURN protocols, in an ECS cluster with Fargate to support Otter's P2P connectivity.
- Built a simple API for developers to integrate Otter's functionality within their web applications.
- Secured HTTP/WebSocket API Gateways by using an API key and JSON Web Tokens.
- Optimized Otter for low latency by reducing the number of reads to DynamoDB.
- Authored a technical case study on the design decisions and engineering challenges faced while building Otter.

Launch School Apr 2022 – Dec 2022

Attended a mastery-based education program focused on software engineering fundamentals.

- ReAck: An application for collecting and inspecting HTTP webhook requests. ReAck is built with React, Node.js (Express framework), PostgreSQL, MongoDB, and Nginx.
- Rate Your Dinner: An application for rating culinary experiences. Built with Pug templating engine, Node. is and PostgreSQL.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Actuarial Analyst, Actuarial Services - Consulting

Sep 2021 – Apr 2022 | Toronto

RSM Canada

• Performed the valuation of multiple insurance companies at year-end.

Actuarial Analyst, Corporate Reserving

Feb 2021 – Aug 2021 | Toronto

Northbridge Financial Corporation

Prepared the valuation of the commercial lines of business cumulating to more than \$1 billion.

Actuarial Analyst II, Actuarial Pricing

Jun 2020 – Feb 2021 | Toronto

Wawanesa Insurance

• Analyzed and monitored multiple insurance products on a monthly basis.

Actuarial Analyst, P&C Actuarial Practice - Consulting

Jan 2019 – Jun 2020 | Toronto

KPMG Canada

Participated in the audit of over 20 clients during year-ends and contributed to Appointed Actuary work.

SKILLS

Frontend JavaScript, React, HTML, and CSS

Backend

Node.js, Go, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, and RESTful APIs **AWS Cloud**

Lambda, ECS, EC2, Fargate, API Gateway, CloudFront, S3, NLB, IAM, and DynamoDB

Other

TypeScript, WebRTC, Docker, Nginx, Git, WebSocket, and Webhooks

EDUCATION

Software Engineering & Full-Stack Web Development Launch School

2022

Université de Montréal